Guide to the David Newton Henderson Papers, 1930-1976 RL.00528
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- County Project Files Series
  - Multicounty Projects
    - Trent River Flood Control, 1961-1966 (Box 177)
    - White Oak River, 1955 - 1970 (Box 177)
  - Miscellaneous Projects
    - Airports, 1961-1966 (Box 177)
    - Armories, 1961-1970 (Box 177)
    - Army Reserve Units, 1966-1967 (Box 177)
    - Corps of Engineers, 1953-1964 (Box 177)
    - Corps of Engineers, 1965-1972 (Box 178)
    - County Roads (photographs), 1973 (Box 178)
    - The Duke Endowment, 1968.Information on contributions made by the Duke Endowment in the Third District. (Box 178)
    - Educational Statistics- Third Congressional District, 1961 (Box 178)
    - Harbors of Refuge, 1961 (Box 178)
    - Hospitals, 1947-1961 (Box 178)
    - Hurricane Protection, 1958-1965 (Box 178)
    - Industrial Education Centers, 1958-1963 (Box 178)
    - Military Bases, 1964-1968 (Box 178)
    - Miscellany, 1949-1970 (Box 179)
    - Miscellany, 1971 (Box 180)
    - Navigation Aids, 1955-1960 (Box 180)
    - North Carolina State Port Authority Projects, 1946-1968, 1972 (Box 180)
    - Poverty Program Projects, 1966-1970 (Box 181)
    - Rivers and Harbors, 1950-1970 (Box 181)
    - Schools. Civil Rights Compliance Plans, 1965-1970 (Box 181)
    - Soil Conservation, undated (Box 181)
    - Stream Clearance, 1956-1961 (Box 181)
    - Water and Sewer Projects, 1965-1970 (Box 181)
    - Watershed Projects, 1965-1966 (Box 181)
- Engagements Series
  Includes invitations received by Henderson's office and correspondence and printed material relating to accepted engagements. This material illustrates lobbying efforts of both local and national interest groups, businesses and organizations. These papers also reveal something of Henderson's daily schedule. Materials were left in the arrangement as they were filed by Henderson's office. Accepted invitations were filed by following the date of the engagements. Declined invitations were filed as they crossed Henderson's desk, i.e. at the time when Henderson's staff responded to the invitation.
  - Appointment Books:
    - 1968 (Box 182)
    - 1969 (Box 182)
    - 1971 (Box 182)
    - 1972 (Box 182)
  - Schedules. Miscellaneous:
    - 1969 (Box 182)
    - 1970 (Box 182)
    - 1971 (Box 182)
    - Undated (Box 182)
  - Engagements. Accepted:
    - 1960 (Box 183)
    - 1961 (Box 183)
    - 1962 (Box 183)
    - 1963 (Box 183)
    - 1965 (Box 183)
    - 1966 (Box 184)
    - 1968 (Box 184)
    - 1969 (Box 184)
    - 1970 (Box 185)
    - 1971 (Box 185)
    - 1972 (Box 186)
    - 1973 (Box 186)
    - 1974 (Box 187)
    - 1975, January-April (Box 187)
    - 1975, May-December (Box 188)
    - 1976 (Box 189)
  - Engagements. Declined:
    - 1961 (Box 190)
    - 1962 (Box 190)
    - 1963 (Box 191)
    - 1965 (Box 191)
    - 1966 (Box 192)
    - 1969, January-March (Box 192)
    - 1969, April-December (Box 193)
    - 1970, January-June (Box 193)
    - 1970, July-December (Box 194)
    - 1971, January-September (Box 194)
    - 1971, October-December (Box 195)
    - 1972 (Box 195)
    - 1973, January-July (Box 196)
    - 1973, August-December (Box 197)
    - 1974, January-April (Box 197)
    - 1974, May-December (Box 198)
    - 1975, January-April (Box 199)
    - 1975, May-November (Box 200)
    - 1975, December (Box 201)
    - 1976, January-April (Box 201)
    - 1976, May-December (Box 202)
- Federal and State Agencies Series
  Contains mainly correspondence reflecting Henderson's role as an intermediary between constituents' problems and appropriate federal and state agencies which could resolve those problems. There is some expression of opinion by constituents over the activities, regulations, and administration of such agencies. These papers are similar to the Case Files in nature. Folder headings for North Carolina departments and agencies are preceded by N.C. Those without this indication are federal agencies. Each agency is listed alphabetically even if it is part of a larger department or agency. State and federal agencies are filed separately.
  - North Carolina Agencies
    - Administration, Department of, 1974-1975 (Box 203)
    - Agriculture, Department of, 1961-1976 (Box 203)
    - Attorney General, Office of, 1973-1975 (Box 203)
    - Commerce, Department of, 1975-1976 (Box 203)
    - Community Colleges, Division of, 1975 (Box 203)
    - Conservation and Development, Department of, 1967-1974 (Box 204)
    - Cultural Resources, Department of, 1975 (Box 204)
    - Education, Department of, 1961-1976 (Box 204)
    - Employment Security Division, 1968-1972 (Box 204)
    - General Assembly, 1961-1975 (Box 205)
    - Governor's Office, 1974-1975 (Box 205)
    - Highway Commission, 1961-1972 (Box 205)
    - Highway Commission, 1973-1976 (Box 206)
    - Human Resources, Department of, 1975-1976 (Box 206)
    - Insurance, Department of, 1975 (Box 206)
    - Labor, Department of, 1975 (Box 206)
    - Manpower Development Training Program, 1967-1968 (Box 206)
    - Mental Health, Division of, 1975 (Box 206)
    - National Guard, 1967-1976 (Box 206)
    - Natural and Economic Resources, Department of, 1975-1976 (Box 206)
    - Public Welfare, Department of, 1967-1971 (Box 206)
    - Secretary of State, Office of, 1975 (Box 206)
    - Social Services, Department of, 1972-1973, 1975-1976 (Box 207)
    - State Board of Elections, 1968-1972 (Box 207)
    - Transportation, Department of, 1975-1976 (Box 207)
    - Utilities Commission, 1972 (Box 207)
    - Water and Air Resources, Department of, 1961-1972 (Box 207)
    - Wildlife Resources Commission, 1975-1976 (Box 207)
    - Miscellaneous State Agencies, 1968-1971 (Box 208)
    - Miscellaneous State Agencies, 1972-1976 (Box 209)
  - United States Agencies
    - Agricultural Marketing Service (Department of Agriculture), 1976 (Box 210)
    - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service (Department of Agriculture), 1961-1971 (Box 210)
    - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service (Department of Agriculture), 1972-1976 (Box 211)
    - Agriculture, Department of, 1961-1964 (Box 211)
    - Agriculture, Department of, 1965-1969 (Box 212)
    - Agriculture, Department of, 1970-1973 (Box 213)
    - Agriculture, Department of, 1974-1976 (Box 214)
    - Air Force, Department of the (Department of Defense), 1960-1976 (Box 215)
    - Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms, Bureau of (Department of the Treasury), 1975-1976 (Box 215)
    - Area Redevelopment Administration (Department of Commerce), 1963-1965 (Box 215)
    - Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, 1967 (Box 215)
    - Army, Department of the (Department of Defense), 1961-1966 (Box 215)
    - Army, Department of the (Department of Defense), 1967-1972 (Box 216)
    - Army, Department of the (Department of Defense), 1973-1976 (Box 217)
    - Atomic Energy Commission, 1961, 1968-1973 (Box 217)
    - Census, Bureau of the (Department of Commerce), 1968-1973, 1975 (Box 217)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, 1973, 1975 (Box 217)
    - Civil Aeronautics Board, 1970-1971, 1973-1974, 1976 (Box 218)
    - Civil Service Commission, 1961-1970 (Box 218)
    - Civil Service Commission, 1971-1976 (Box 219)
    - Coast Guard (Department of the Treasury), 1960-1961, 1963-1967 (Box 219)
    - Coast Guard (Department of the Treasury), 1968-1975 (Box 220)
    - Coast Guard, Navigation Aids, 1963-1966 (Box 220)
    - Coastal Plains Regional Commission, 1965-1975 (Box 220)
    - Coastal Zone Management, Office of (National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, Department of Commerce), 1974 (Box 221)
    - Commerce, Department of, 1961-1976 (Box 221)
    - Consumer Product Safety Commission, 1975 (Box 221)
    - Consumer Protection Agency (see Subject Files. Consumer Protection Agency) (Box 221)
    - Corps of Engineers (Department of the Army), 1975-1976 (Box 221)
    - Cost of Living Council, 1973-1975.Concerns Nixon's wage-price freeze. (Box 222)
    - Customs Service (Department of the Treasury), 1975 (Box 222)
    - Defense, Department of, 1960-1970 (Box 222)
    - Defense, Department of, 1971-1976 (Box 223)
    - Defense, Department of. Moving and Storage Realignment, 1970 (Box 223)
    - Drug Enforcement Administration (Department of Justice), 1976 (Box 224)
    - Economic Development Administration (Department of Commerce), 1965-1976 (Box 224)
    - Economic Opportunity, Office of, 1965-1970 (Box 224)
    - Economic Opportunity, Office of, 1971-1977 (Box 225)
    - Education, Office of (Department of Health, Education, and Welfare), 1966-1974 (Box 225)
    - Education, Office of (Department of Health, Education, and Welfare), 1975-1976 (Box 226)
    - Education, Office of. Revised Guidelines Regarding Desegregation, 1966-1967 (Box 226)
    - Emergency Preparedness, Office of, 1971.Concerns price-wage freeze. (Box 226)
    - Energy Research and Development Administration, 1976 (Box 226)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, 1971-1976 (Box 227)
    - Environmental Science Services Administration (Department of Commerce), 1966 (Box 227)
    - Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 1965, 1969, 1975-1976 (Box 227)
    - Farmers Home Administration (Department of Agriculture), 1961-1976 (Box 228)
    - Federal Aviation Agency, 1960-1976 (Box 229)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation (Department of Justice), 1962-1976 (Box 230)
    - Federal Communications Commission, 1961-1967 (Box 230)
    - Federal Communications Commission, 1968-1976 (Box 231)
    - Federal Crop Insurance Corporation (Department of Agriculture), 1967, 1970-1972 (Box 231)
    - Federal Election Commission, 1976 (Box 231)
    - Federal Energy Administration, 1974-1976 (Box 232)
    - Federal Executive Institute (Civil Service Commission), 1975 (Box 232)
    - Federal Highway Administration (Department of Transportation), 1973-1976 (Box 232)
    - Federal Home Loan Bank Board, 1975 (Box 232)
    - Federal Housing Administration (Housing and Home Finance Agency to 1965, Department of Housing and Urban Development, 1965 on), 1962-1967, 1973-1975 (Box 232)
    - Federal Maritime Commission, 1969, 1975 (Box 232)
    - Federal Power Commission, 1961-1963, 1974-1975 (Box 232)
    - Federal Reserve Board, 1971-1975 (Box 232)
    - Federal Trade Commission, 1962-1976 (Box 233)
    - Fish and Wildlife Service (Department of the Interior), 1961-1973 (Box 233)
    - Food and Drug Administration (Department of Health, Education, and Welfare), 1963-1971 (Box 233)
    - Food and Drug Administration (Department of Health, Education, and Welfare), 1972-1976 (Box 234)
    - Forest Service (Department of Agriculture), 1961-1972 (Box 234)
    - Forest Service (Department of Agriculture), 1973-1975 (Box 235)
    - General Accounting Office, 1966, 1969-1975 (Box 235)
    - General Services Administration, 1961-1976 (Box 235)
    - Government Printing Office, 1961-1976 (Box 236)
    - Health, Education, and Welfare, Department of, 1960-1967.see also Subject Files. HEW Appropriation Veto, 1970 (Box 236)
    - Health, Education, and Welfare, Department of, 1968-1971 (Box 237)
    - Health, Education, and Welfare, Department of, 1972-1974 (Box 238)
    - Health, Education, and Welfare, Department of, 1975-1976 (Box 239)
    - Housing and Home Finance Agency, 1961-1966 (Box 239)
    - Housing and Urban Development, Department of, 1965-1976 (Box 240)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service (Department of Justice), 1961-1975 (Box 241)
    - Indian Affairs, Bureau of (Department of the Interior), 1974 (Box 241)
    - Interior, Department of the, 1960-1970 (Box 241)
    - Interior, Department of the, 1971-1976 (Box 242)
    - Internal Revenue Service (Department of the Treasury), 1961-1976 (Box 243)
    - International Development, Agency for, (Department of State), 1975-1976 (Box 244)
    - International Trade Commission, 1976 (Box 244)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission, 1962-1976 (Box 244)
    - Justice, Department of, 1961-1969 (Box 244)
    - Justice, Department of, 1970-1976 (Box 245)
    - Labor, Department of, 1961-1966 (Box 245)
    - Labor, Department of, 1968-1976 (Box 246)
    - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration (Department of Justice), 1975 (Box 247)
    - Library of Congress, 1961-1976 (Box 247)
    - Management and Budget, Office of, 1973-1974.Concerns proposed cuts in the federal budget. (Box 248)
    - Manpower Administration (Department of Labor), 1967-1973 (Box 248)
    - Marine Corps (Department of the Navy), 1960-1970 (Box 248)
    - Marine Corps (Department of the Navy), 1971-1976 (Box 249)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration, 1962-1975 (Box 249)
    - National Capitol Housing Authority, 1967-1968 (Box 249)
    - National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities, 1966, 1970, 1973 (Box 249)
    - National Institute of Health (Department of Health, Education, and Welfare), 1974-1976 (Box 249)
    - National Park Service (Department of the Interior), 1966-1976 (Box 249)
    - Navy, Department of the (Department of Defense), 1961-1976 (Box 250)
    - Oil and Gas, Office of, 1973, January-JuneConcerns petroleum shortage of 1973. (Box 250)
      The following folders deal with Henderson's efforts as an intermediary between local petroleum dealers and federal energy authorities in the allocation of gas during the shortage.
    - Oil and Gas, Office of, 1973, July-December (Box 251)
    - Oil and Gas, Office of, 1974 (Box 251)
    - Oil and Gas Cases:
      - Amon, Ray, 1974 (Box 251)
      - Ashford Oil Company, 1974-1975 (Box 251)
      - Aycock, George, 1974 (Box 251)
      - Barefoot-McLamb Oil Co., 1974-1975 (Box 251)
      - Brisson Oil Co., Bladenboro, N.C., 1974 (Box 251)
      - Brown Oil Co., 1974 (Box 251)
      - C. D. Cain Oil Co., 1973-1974 (Box 251)
      - Cities Service Oil Co., 1974 (Box 251)
      - Coats Distributors, Inc., 1974 (Box 251)
      - Collier Oil Co., 1974 (Box 251)
      - Dees, Bobby, undated (Box 252)
      - E. and B. Oil Co. (T. J. Baker), 1973-1974 (Box 252)
      - Edwards Oil Co. (J. G. Aycock), 1974 (Box 252)
      - Etheridge Oil Co., 1974 (Box 252)
      - Eubanks Oil Co., 1974 (Box 252)
      - Fountain, Stacy, 1974 (Box 252)
      - Great Gas and Oil (Bobby S. Williams, Owner), 1974 (Box 252)
      - Guilford National, 1973-1974 (Box 252)
      - Hollowell Oil Co., New Hope Oil Co., 1973-1974 (Box 252)
      - Jarmon Oil Co., 1974-1975 (Box 252)
      - Kelly's Oil Co. (Billy Ray Cameron), 1974 (Box 252)
      - A. G. Lee Oil Co., 1974 (Box 252)
      - T. R. Lee Oil Co., 1974 (Box 252)
      - Mack Oil Co. (Larry McCullen), 1974 (Box 252)
      - McKinley Price Oil Co. (D. M. Price Oil Co.), 1974 (Box 252)
      - Myslinski, E. J. (Ski's Texaco), 1974 (Box 252)
      - New Hope Oil Co., 1974 (Box 252)
      - N. C. Lime Excavating Co., Comfort, N.C., 1974 (Box 252)
      - Onslow Oil Co. (K. D. Thompson), 1974-1975 (Box 252)
      - Palmer-Reeves Co., Inc., L. P. Wilkins, Pres., 1974 (Box 252)
      - Pope, E. J., Oil Co., 1974-1976 (Box 252)
      - Potter Oil Co., H. L. (Sonny) Blaylock, 1974 (Box 252)
      - D. M. Price Oil Co., 1974 (Box 252)
      - Quality Auto Parts, 1974 (Box 252)
      - Rackley, Felton, 1974 (Box 253)
      - Sandlin, Hugh, 1974 (Box 253)
      - Selma Auto Center, Misc., 1976 (Box 253)
      - Smithfield Oil and Gas Co., Inc., Marvin Johnson, 1974 (Box 253)
      - Spivey Oil Co., 1974 (Box 253)
      - Strickland Oil Co., 1974 (Box 253)
      - Strickland, John, 1974 (Box 253)
      - Stroud's Grill and Groc., 1974 (Box 253)
      - Taylor's Amoco Gas Station (Sam Taylor), Bird Oil Co., 1975 (Box 253)
      - Triangle Service Center, 1974 (Box 253)
      - United Maintenance Service, Charles Marsalis, Owner, 1974 (Box 253)
      - Wayne County Ser. Sta. Operators Assn., undated (Box 253)
      - Williford, Cliff, Ecno Oil Co., Inc., 1974 (Box 253)
      - Wilson, Bobby, 1974 (Box 253)
      - Wooten, Sterling, 1974 (Box 253)
      - Wooten Oil Co., Dillon Wooten, 1974-1976 (Box 253)
      - Worsley Oil Co. (Do and Save Exxon), 1976 (Box 253)
    - Parole, Board of (Department of Justice), 1975 (Box 253)
    - Patent Office (Department of Commerce), 1975 (Box 253)
    - Peace Corps (Department of State to 1971, independent after 1971 ), 1961-1963, 1967-1970 (Box 253)
    - Post Office, Department of, 1961-1962.Reorganized, 1970-1971,and renamed Postal Service. (Box 253)
    - Post Office, Department of, 1963-1968 (Box 254)
    - Post Office, Department of, 1969 (Box 255)
    - Post Office, Department of, 1970 (Box 256)
    - Postal Rate Commission, 1975 (Box 256)
    - Postal Service, 1971 (Box 257)
    - Postal Service, 1972-1973 (Box 258)
    - Postal Service, 1974 (Box 259)
    - Postal Service, 1975 (Box 260)
    - Postal Service, 1976 (Box 261)
    - Postal Service. Newsletters, 1971-1972 (Box 261)
    - Price Commission, 1972-1973 (Box 261)
    - Prisons, Bureau of (Department of Justice), 1976 (Box 261)
    - Public Health Service (Department of Health, Education, and Welfare), 1976 (Box 261)
    - Public Roads, Bureau of (Department of Commerce), 1967 (Box 261)
    - Rural Electrification Administration (Department of Agriculture), 1960-1973 (Box 262)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission, 1963, 1969-1970, 1974 (Box 263)
    - Selective Service System, 1961-1976.See also Subject Files: Draftees. (Box 263)
    - Small Business Administration, 1961-1967 (Box 263)
    - Small Business Administration, 1968-1976 (Box 264)
    - Small Business Administration. Loans, 1962-1966 (Box 264)
    - Social Security Administration (Department of Health, Education, and Welfare), 1967-1971 (Box 264)
    - Social Security Administration (Department of Health, Education, and Welfare), 1972-1976 (Box 265)
    - State, Department of, 1961-1967 (Box 265)
    - State, Department of, 1964-1976 (Box 266)
    - Supreme Court, 1963-1974 (Box 266)
    - Transportation, Department of, 1966-1970 (Box 266)
    - Transportation, Department of, 1971-1976 (Box 267)
    - Treasury, Department of, 1962-1971 (Box 267)
    - Treasury, Department of, 1972-1976 (Box 268)
    - Veterans Administration, 1967-1976.See also Subject Files: Direct VA loans. (Box 268)
- Legislation Series
  Contains copies and drafts of specific bills, informative material about the bills, committee reports and statements, and Henderson's notes on such specific pieces of legislation. For public opinion on bills, see Subject Files. This category is not a complete file of every bill passing through Congress during Henderson's years; much of this legislation reflects Henderson's committee memberships and bills of local interest. The papers are arranged by Congress and session and specific bill number. A comprehensive listing of the title and number of each bill in this category is located at the beginning of the first box of Legislation files.
  - 87th Congress, 1st Session, 1961 (Box 269-272)
  - 87th Congress, 2nd Session, 1962 (Box 273-275)
  - 88th Congress, 1st Session, 1963 (Box 276-277)
  - 88th Congress, 2nd Session, 1964 (Box 278)
  - 89th Congress, 1st Session, 1965 (Box 279-280)
  - 89th Congress, 2nd Session, 1966 (Box 280-281)
  - 90th Congress, 1st Session, 1967 (Box 282)
  - 90th Congress, 2nd Session, 1968 (Box 283)
  - 91st Congress, 1st Session, 1969 (Box 284)
  - 91st Congress, 2nd Session, 1970 (Box 285)
  - 92nd Congress, 1st Session, 1971 (Box 286-288)
  - 92nd Congress, 2nd Session, 1972 (Box 289)
  - 93d Congress, 1st Session, 1973 (Box 290-292)
  - 93d Congress, 2nd Session, 1974 (Box 293)
  - 94th Congress, 1st Session, 1975 (Box 294-295)
  - 94th Congress, 2nd Session, 1976 (Box 296)
  - Miscellany (Box 297)
- Military Academy Files
  Contains general information about the service academies and guidelines for congressmen in their appointment of candidates for openings at the academies. Application materials and academic records of Third District appointees have been removed from this collection and destroyed. The Buckley Amendment of 1967 to the Priacy Act prohibits the use of such materials without the individual's written consent.
  - Air Force Academy, 1959-1974 (Box 298)
  - Coast Guard Academy, 1959-1970 (Box 298)
  - Merchant Marine Academy, 1957-1974 (Box 298)
  - Military Academy, West Point, 1960-1974 (Box 299)
  - Naval Academy, 1959-1970 (Box 299)
  - Naval Academy, 1971-1974 (Box 300)
  - Miscellany, 1962-1974 (Box 300)
- Newsletters and News Releases Series
  Henderson's office sent weekly newsletters to constituents which dealt with national affairs, current legislation, and Henderson's policies and views. Frequent topics included civil rights, Vietnam, and foreign aid. The news releases were bulletins sent to newspapers and radio and television stations. This series also contains letters from constituents responding to the newsletters.
  - Newsletters and News Releases:
    - 1962-1969 (Box 301)
    - 1970-1973 (Box 302)
    - 1974-1976 (Box 303)
  - Reader Comments:
    - 1969-1971 (Box 304)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 305)
    - 1974-June, 1975 (Box 306)
    - 1975, July-1976 (Box 307)
- Newspaper Clippings Series
  Contains mostly clippings of publicity Henderson received in newspapers in the Third Congressional District.
  - 1961-1962 (Box 308)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 309)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 310)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 311)
  - 1969, 1970, January-June (Box 312)
  - 1970, July-December (Box 313)
  - Cape Lookout National Seashore, 1966 (Box 313)
  - Henderson- Lennon Interviews with the Wilmington Star, 1968-1969 (Box 313)
  - Robert Morgan, 1965-1966 (Box 313)
  - Miscellany, 1966-1968 (Box 313)
- Post Office Files Series
  Contains correspondence and notes concerning the building of new post office facilities and consolidation of some local post offices in the Third District. Also contains much material about the appointment of personnel. Files for local post offices were retained only for Morehead City and county seats.
  - General Material:
    - Civil Post Offices at Military Installations, 1967-1968 (Box 314)
    - First Class Post Offices, 1961 (Box 314)
    - Highway and Railroad Post Offices, 1966-1967 (Box 314)
    - Star Routes, 1956-1967 (Box 314)
    - Miscellany, 1952-1970 (Box 314)
  - Counties:
    - Carteret County, 1961 (Box 315)
    - Craven County, 1961 (Box 315)
    - Duplin County, 1961 (Box 315)
    - Harnett County, 1961 (Box 315)
    - Jones County, 1961 (Box 315)
    - Onslow County, 1961-1964 (Box 315)
    - Pamlico County, 1960-1961 (Box 315)
    - Pender County, 1961 (Box 315)
    - Sampson County, 1961 (Box 315)
    - Wayne County, 1961 (Box 315)
  - County Seats:
    - Bayboro, 1960-1965 (Box 315)
    - Beaufort, 1961-1976 (Box 315)
    - Burgaw, 1958-1975 (Box 315)
    - Clinton, 1960-1976 (Box 316)
    - Goldsboro, 1960-1970 (Box 316)
    - Goldsboro. New Route, 1966-1968 (Box 316)
    - Goldsboro. Postmaster, 1962 (Box 317)
    - Goldeboro. Postmaster. B. J. Bowden, 1961-1962 (Box 317)
    - Jacksonville, 1960-1971 (Box 318)
    - Kenansville, 1961-1974 (Box 318)
    - Lillington, 1961-1974 (Box 318)
    - New Bern, 1960-1974 (Box 319)
    - Sanford, 1966-1968 (Box 319)
    - Smithfield, 1967-1974 (Box 319)
    - Trenton, 1961-1967 (Box 319)
    - Morehead City, 1961-1972 (Box 319)
- Speeches Series
  Contains copies of speeches given by Henderson, also correspondence, notes, and background material pertaining to the speeches and speaking engagements. Most speeches were given in the Third District at schools, colleges, rallies, civic clubs, dedications of public facilities, etc. Included also are some speeches made by Henderson in the House of Representatives (see also Subject Files. Congressional Record Remarks) and around the country. Speeches concerned national affairs, especially Vietnam and civil rights, and local projects and concerns. The speeches are arranged chronologically.
  - 1960-1964 (Box 320)
  - 1965-1967 (Box 321)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 322)
  - 1970-1972 (Box 323)